"Poirot" -A band, a band!
"Poirot" -Sebuah band!
Let's the three of us start a girls' high school band!
Kita harus mendirikan sebuah band wanita SMA!
What?
Apa?
Where's all this coming from?
Dari mana datangnya itu?
The movie of a girls' high school band that I was watching last night
Band wanita SMA yang kulihat di film semalam
was super cute.
sangat imut!
Really?
Benarkah?
And?
Dan?
What musical instrument are we going to play, Sonoko?
Sonoko, instrumen apa yang akan kau mainkan?
Of course drums!
Drum, tentunya!
The girl drummer in that band looked like me.
Pemain drum dalam band itu mirip seperti aku.
She was awesome.
Dia sangat keren.
I see.
Begitu.
Then, I'll...
Maka aku akan memainkan...
Since you've got long black hair,
Ran, karena kau berambut hitam panjang,
you're playing the bass, you're the bassist!
kau akan memainkan bas!
What?
Apa?
The bassist in that band had hair like yours too.
Pemain bas band itu memiliki rambut yang sama!
But I never played bass before.
Tapi aku tak pernah memainkan bas sebelumnya.
You're better at playing the piano, right, Ran?
Ran, kau lebih baik dalam piano, bukan?
Maybe I should play bass?
Ingin aku memainkan basnya?
Big brother's friend taught me how to play bass before.
Teman kakakku mengajariku dulu sekali.
Okay, Sera, you play bass
Maka Sera akan memainkan basnya.
and Ran, will you play the keyboard then?
Ran, bisakah kau memainkan keyboard?
Okay.
Tentu...
But, where are we going to be performing?
Tapi di mana kita akan tampil?
"Looking For Performers, Beika-cho Countdown Talent Show"
"Mencari Penampil Pertunjukkan Bakat Hitung Mundur Beika-cho"
We'll perform at the end of the year countdown talent show in Beika-cho
Kita akan tampil pada pertunjukkan bakat akhir tahun di Beika-cho,
and win the championship!
dan keluar dengan gelar pemenangnya!
But don't we need a guitarist for the band too?
Tapi bukankah band kita akan butuh seorang gitaris?
You're right,
Ya,
but there's no one in class who looks to be able to play the guitar.
tapi sepertinya tidak ada siapapun di kelas kita yang bisa bermain gitar.
Azusa!
Azusa!
Will you wipe the table, please?
Bisakah kau bersihkan meja ini?
Oh, okay.
Tentu.
I found a guitarist!
Gitaris kita!
What?
Apa?
There was a girl named Azusa,
Band wanita SMA itu
who played the guitar well in that high school girls band too!
punya seorang gadis bernama Azusa yang pintar memainkan gitar!
But I never ever touched a guitar.
Tapi aku bahkan tak pernah menyentuh sebuah gitar.
And, besides, I'm not even in high school to begin with.
Dan aku bukan anak SMA.
If you wear a uniform, nobody would know!
Tidak akan ada yang tahu jika kau mengenakan seragam.
Besides, you have pretty much of a baby face too, Azusa!
Di samping itu, kau punya wajah bayi!
Baby face?
Wajah bayi?
She's completely poisoned by that movie.
Film itu jelas berdampak negatif padanya.
But, isn't a guitar difficult to play?
Tapi bukankah memainkan gitar itu sulit?
You'll be just fine, don't worry.
Kau akan baik-baik saja.
Just a little practice and you be able to play in no time!
Dengan sedikit latihan, kau akan langsung bisa memainkannya!
Strum, strum.
Petik, petik.
Okay, play then!
Maka, kau yang mainkan!
Here, I'll lend you my guitar.
Kau bisa meminjam gitarku.
Oh, but...
Oh, tapi...
We'll hook it up to our portable amp,
Kami akan menyambungkannya ke ampli portabel kami.
so you can play right away.
Kau bisa langsung bermain.
Go ahead!
Ini.
No...
Sebenarnya...
You said with a little practice, you could play in no time, right?
Kupikir dengan sedikit latihan, kau bisa segera bermain.
If so, show me what you can do, young lady.
Jadi kenapa kau tidak tunjukkan pada kami di sini, nona?
A canvas stained black with crime.
Sebuah kanvas ternoda hitam dengan kejahatan.
Vivid brilliant deduction skills change its color.
Dengan kemampuan detektif yang brilian, warnanya berubah.
What will happen to Sonoko?
Apa yang akan Sonoko lakukan?
I guess there are great expectations for the three member of the JK band!
Tapi harapannya tinggi untuk trio band wanita SMA itu!
He sees through the one and only truth.
Dia melihat satu-satunya kebenaran.
A child in appearance with the I.Q. of an adult.
Memiliki penampilan seorang anak kecil dengan kepintaran orang dewasa.
His name is Detective Conan!
Namanya adalah Detektif Conan!
"A Girls' Band on Bad Terms (Part 1)"
"Band Wanita Yang Tidak Ramah (Bagian 1)"
In the movie, I think the fingers were place like this.
Dalam film itu, kurasa mereka melakukan ini dengan jari mereka.
Come on, you can't even play.
Apa ini? Kau bahkan tak bisa bermain.
You've got the nerve, when you can't even play!
Kalau tak bisa, jangan belagu!
High school girl!
Gadis kecil!
Sonoko.
Sonoko.
Hand it over.
Aku pinjam.
Wow.
Wow.
He's good!
Dia sangat hebat!
Well, if they practice a little,
Dengan sedikit latihan,
they'll be able to play this in no time at all, right?
bahkan para gadis ini bisa belajar untuk memainkan itu. Benar?
Sure.
Ya.
Yes.
Benar.
You're right.
Kau benar.
Sonoko, you should watch your big mouth too.
Sonoko, kau harus jaga mulut besarmu itu.
Okay.
Baik.
Thank you very much!
Terima kasih!
Amuro, please join our band!
Amuro, kau harus bergabung dengan band kami!
What?
Apa?
Then, we can have a girls' high school plus handsome band, right?
Kita bisa mendirikan band wanita SMA dan pria tampan, bukan?
I don't think so.
Aku tidak begitu yakin.
I don't like to stand out, you see.
Aku tidak suka menarik perhatian pada diriku.
Well, after all, you're a security police agent
Yah, dia adalah polisi keamanan
that's infiltrated the Black Organization so...
yang menyusup ke Organisasi Hitam...
I can help you out when you practice, though.
Tapi, aku bisa membantumu latihan.
Would you like to go to a rental studio
Apa kau mau pergi ke studio rental
and practice a little from now?
dan latihan sedikit sekarang?
-That sounds good! -Yes, let's!
-Ide bagus! -Ayo kita lakukan itu!
Hey, you.
Hei, kau.
Haven't we met somewhere before?
Apa kita pernah bertemu sebelumnya?
No.
Tidak.
I think today's the first time.
Aku yakin hari ini adalah kali pertama kita bertemu.
Oh, no?
Apa? Tidak mungkin!
All the rooms are full?
Semua ruangannya penuh?
It'll be a one hour wait.
Satu seharusnya tersedia sekitar satu jam lagi.
What shall we do?
Apa yang harus kita lakukan?
Maybe some other time then?
Haruskah kita kembali nanti?
But, we came all this way.
Tapi kita sudah datang jauh-jauh ke sini.
Well, if it's just an hour, maybe we should wait?
Kita bisa menunggu satu jam.
There seems to be a break room on the basement floor too.
Mereka ada ruang istirahat di ruang bawah.
If we rent the instruments,
Jika kita menyewa alat musik,
I can at least teach you the feel of a song
kau setidaknya bisa mempelajari nuansa lagu
by playing note for note and the chords.
melalui akord dan nada.
Oh, you can play the bass too?
Benarkah? Kau juga bisa memainkan bas?
Yes.
Ya,
Although I can't guarantee that I'm better than your big brother's friend.
walau aku tak bisa menjamin aku lebih baik dari teman kakakmu.
By the way, can you play the drums, Sonoko?
Ngomong-ngomong, Sonoko, bisakah kau memainkan drumnya?
Of course!
Tentu saja!
I'm great at Drum Master!
Aku Ahli Drum yang hebat.
A video game, huh?
Itu hanya game.
Sera, you're fantastic!
Sera, itu menakjubkan!
You're good!
Bagus!
I just played the scale.
Yang aku lakukan adalah memainkan tangga nadanya.
Well, but the only thing that my brother's friend taught me
Lagipula, teman kakakku hanya mengajariku
was till here though.
sampai di sini.
Really?
Benarkah?
Do you remember the face of the guy who taught you how to play the bass?
Apa kau ingat seperti apa rupa pria yang mengajarimu bas?
Well, sort of.
Kurang lebih.
But how did you know that his friend was a guy?
Tapi bagaimana kau tahu teman kakakku adalah seorang pria?
Well, I just happened to think so.
Hanya sebuah firasat.
Come on!
Ayolah!
At this rate, we won't make it in time!
Pada tahap ini, kita takkan berhasil tepat waktu!
We've only got a week to go before the live, you know!
Kita hanya punya waktu seminggu sebelum konser itu!
Tadako, your bass is off rhythm,
Tadako, basmu salah nada,
and your voice isn't projecting either!
dan aku tak bisa mendengarmu sama sekali!
Sorry, I over drank yesterday.
Maaf, aku terlalu banyak minum kemarin.
And Rumi, your keyboard played the wrong sound at times!
Rumi, keyboardmu berantakan!
I'll bet your nails are long!
Kau tidak memotong kuku jarimu, ya?
Sorry. I haven't been playing the keyboard recently.
Maaf, aku sudah lama tidak bermain.
And Hagie, your drumming was more sluggish than always.
Dan, Hagie, drummu terasa lebih lamban dari biasanya.
"Hagie Yamaji (25), Drums (Leader)" -Sorry.
"Hagie Yamaji (25), Drum (Pemimpin)" -Maaf.
"Hagie Yamaji (25), Drums (Leader)" -I'm kind of sleepy, you see.
"Hagie Yamaji (25), Drum (Pemimpin)" -Aku sangat lelah.
Come on, shape up, everybody!
Yang benar, kalian!
Someka, your guitar was a bit too fast too.
Tapi, Someka, gitarmu terlalu cepat.
It was like you were annoyed or something.
Kau tampak kesal.
Like I said, we don't have much time left.
Karena kita kehabisan waktu.
You don't seem to notice that your button's about to fall off too.
Dan kau belum menyadari bahwa kancingmu hampir lepas.
-What? -The chest pocket to the left.
-Apa? -Pada saku kiri dadamu.
Well, let's cool our heads off a bit and resume practice.
Bagaimanapun, kita akan kembali begitu kita sudah menenangkan pikiran kita.
I'm going back to the studio to take a quick nap till then.
Hingga saat itu, aku akan tidur di studio.
I should be okay after a 10 minute nap.
Aku seharusnya membaik setelah tidur 10 menit.
Gosh.
Astaga.
We only have two more hours in the studio.
Kita hanya punya waktu dua jam lagi di studio.
What should I do about my nails?
Apa yang harus kulakukan tentang kukuku?
Would you like to use my nail clipper?
Mau pakai gunting kukuku?
Thank you. I'll go cut my nails in the restroom later.
Terima kasih. Aku akan memotongnya di kamar mandi nanti.
Would you like me to sew your button on for you too, Someka?
Someka, ingin aku menjahitkan kancingmu?
I have a sewing kit.
Aku membawa alat jahitku.
You're like a mother, Tadako.
Tadako, kau seperti seorang ibu.
You're good at sewing too.
Kau sangat pandai menjahit.
I'm not as good at knitting as Akane, though.
Tapi, aku tidak sepandai Akane dalam merajut.
Akane knitted the cap that Hagie's wearing too.
Dia membuat topi rajut yang Hagie kenakan.
That's right.
Itu benar.
This is a tribute for Akane, so we have to make it a success!
Ini adalah konser tribut untuk Akane, jadi kita harus mensukseskannya!
And yet, Hagie goes and takes a nap.
Tapi Hagie sedang tidur.
I wonder if she really understands.
Apa dia sungguh memahaminya?
Bummers!
Uh, oh!
I forgot my sewing kit at the studio.
Aku melupakan peralatan menjahitku di studio.
Okay, I'll go wake Hagie up
Aku akan bangunkan Hagie
and while I'm at it, I'll sew your button on for you
selagi menjahitkan kancingmu.
so can you take off your jacket?
Biarkan aku membawa jaketmu.
Okay. But, I'll go wake Hagie up
Tentu. Tapi aku akan membangunkan Hagie.
because I've got to change the guitar string that broke too.
Aku perlu mengganti senar gitarku yang putus.
Oh, there was a part in a song that I wanted to change too.
Ada bagian dari lagunya yang ingin kuubah.
But if Hagie's sleeping in the studio, I guess I can't.
Tapi jika Hagie sedang tidur di studio, kurasa aku tak bisa.
I've got to play the keyboard to write out the notes too.
Aku tak bisa menuliskan musik kecuali aku bisa memainkan keyboardku.
I've got to turn the volume up to tune my guitar too.
Menyetel senar juga membuat suara.
Well, since we've still got time, no need to rush.
Yah, kita masih punya waktu. Tidak perlu terburu-buru.
Okay!
Kau benar!
We'll be playing Yoko Okino's "Dandelion".
Kita sudah memutuskan kau akan memainkan "Dandelion" milik Yoko Okino,
Who's going to be singing it?
siapa yang akan menjadi vokalnya?
What?
Apa?
You are, aren't you, Sonoko?
Sonoko, bukan?
I can't do two things at one time.
Aku tak bisa melakukan banyak hal.
So, would you like to sing it, Sera?
Sera, bisakah kau bernyanyi?
Nah, I pass.
Aku akan lewatkan.
How about your boyfriend, Shinichi?
Bagaimana dengan kekasihmu, Shinichi?
What?
Apa?
I'm sure that he can play the guitar too, can't he?
Aku yakin dia juga bisa memainkan gitarnya.
Shinichi can play the violin.
Shinichi bisa memainkan biola,
But I wonder about the guitar?
tapi aku tidak tahu tentang gitar.
As to singing...
Dan nyanyiannya...
As to singing?
Nyanyiannya?
As to singing, he's on the same level as Conan, right?
Dia bernyanyi seperti Conan. Benar?
Sorry that I'm tone-deaf.
Maaf, aku tuli nada.
Isn't the scream of the people of the band we saw earlier?
Bukankah teriakan itu berasal dari band wanita yang kita lihat barusan?
It came from the studio upstairs, right?
Itu berasal dari studio di atas.
Where did that scream come from?
Dari mana asalnya teriakan itu?
From the studio back there.
Dari studio di belakang sana.
Is she dead?
Apa dia sudah tewas?
Hey! Hagie!
Hei! Hagie!
No joke?
Kau pasti bercanda.
Hagie? Hagie?
Hagie? Hagie?
There's a Yoshikawa line on her neck.
Garis Yoshikawa di lehernya.
She was strangled to death.
Dia dicekik.
Strangled?
Dicekik?
Who did this to Hagie?
Siapa yang mencekik Hagie?
I think we'll be able to figure it out right away.
Aku rasa kita akan segera tahu.
What?
Apa?
See.
Lihat.
We can view the footage from the security camera on the ceiling.
Kita bisa lihat rekaman dari kamera keamanan di atap.
Hey? What the heck is this?
Hei, apa ini?
Half of the image is black and not visible?
Setengah gambarnya hitam.
More so, it's black just by the drums.
Dan drumnya tertutup sepenuhnya.
I think that's behind the cell phone.
Itu mungkin bagian belakang ponsel.
We were filming ourselves practicing.
Kami sedang merekam diri kami yang sedang latihan.
We stuck a selfie stick to the tip of the mic.
Kami pasang tongkat swafoto ke sebuah mik.
I see.
Begitu.
Under these circumstances...
Dengan keadaan ini...
Even if somebody was doing something near the victim...
Walaupun seseorang melakukan sesuatu di sebelah korban...
Nobody would know about it!
Tidak mungkin bagi kita untuk mengetahui apa itu.
I see.
Begitu.
In order to record your practice,
Karena ponsel di tongkat swafoto itu
since you set the cell phone onto the tip of the mic stand,
yang kau pasangkan di dudukan mik
which was attached to the selfie stick, like this,
untuk merekam penampilan kalian,
one side of the image on the security camera was cut off,
gambar kamera keamanannya terpotong setengah,
and the area around the drums was completely out of range
mengamankan area di sekitar drum,
that it's impossible to tell who strangled her.
dan mencegah kami mengetahui siapa yang membunuhnya.
Is that right?
Apa itu benar?
Yes, sir.
Ya.
By the way, who put this here?
Ngomong-ngomong, siapa yang meletakkan ini di sini?
I did.
Aku.
But I wasn't trying to block the security camera or anything.
Aku tidak berusaha untuk menutup kamera keamanannya.
I just set it up like everyone told me to.
Aku hanya meletakkannya di mana aku disuruh.
Right?
Benar?
Yes.
Ya.
We were watching the image on the cell phone
Selagi melihat gambarnya di ponsel,
and told her to move it more to the left.
kami menyuruh dia untuk memindahkannya sedikit ke kiri.
Or more to the rear and things like that.
Atau sedikit lebih ke belakang.
And in the end, I think we decided on the position after Hagie said
Pada akhirnya kami memutuskan posisi untuk meletakkannya saat Hagie bilang,
to set the camera there and start practice.
"Tidak apa-apa. Ayo kita mulai latihan."
But, didn't the shop people scold you?
Apa kalian tidak bermasalah dengan staf studio
After all, you've blocked half the security camera.
karena menutup kamera keamanan?
At first they cautioned us, but...
Kami diperingatkan pada awalnya, tapi...
we're regulars here so they're lenient on us recently.
kami pelanggan tetap, jadi mereka mulai membiarkan kami.
But, why?
Tapi kenapa?
Normally, one part of the wall of rental studios
Biasanya studio satu dinding
is made of mirrored walls like this,
ditutupi cermin
so that the crime being committed is reflected on the mirror
agar pelaku akan terpantul di kaca
and recorded on the security camera.
dan terekam dalam kamera keamanan.
Why were the curtains closed?
Jadi kenapa kau menutup tirainya?
Hagie told us to do so too.
Itu juga Hagie.
She said because she wanted to concentrate on playing.
Dia bilang dia ingin fokus bermain.
She said if we're recording it on the cell phone,
Hingga sudah cukup
watching it later would be good enough.
untuk menonton video yang kami rekam nanti.
Which means this situation was meant to occur.
Yang artinya situasi ini hanya menunggu untuk terjadi.
Yes.
Ya.
The perp who assumed it would turn out this way,
Pelaku pasti telah mengharapkan situasi ini
used it to her advantage.
agar mereka bisa menggunakannya dalam tindak kejahatan mereka.
Well, that is, if you will take the word of a detective.
Jika aku bisa memberikan sudut pandang seorang detektif.
I think it's best to listen to what the three have to say
Bagaimanapun, kita mungkin harus menanyai ketiga gadis itu,
while watching the security camera, no?
selagi menonton rekaman kamera keamanannya.
It seems that all the girls
Tampaknya, mereka bertiga
went in to the studio one after the other to wake Hagie up.
datang ke studio ini satu per satu untuk membangunkan Hagie.
So, we have this coffee shop detective, a high school girl detective
Itu detektif kafe, detektif gadis SMA,
and a grade schooler who believes he's a detective once again.
dan bocah yang berpikir dia adalah seorang detektif lagi.
There sure are a lot of detectives in this town, aren't there?
Kota ini jelas punya banyak detektif.
So, is this how it is?
Beritahu aku jika ini terdengar benar.
You four were taking a break in the basement break room,
Selagi kalian berempat beristirahat di ruang bawah,
Hagie said she wanted to take a nap and went back to the studio.
Hagie bilang dia akan tidur dan kembali ke studio.
The three of you went at different times to wake her,
Satu per satu, kalian pergi untuk membangunkan dia,
but she didn't get up.
tapi dia tetap tidur.
And since she was sleeping for more than 30 minutes,
Karena dia sudah tidur selama lebih dari 30 menit,
all three of you decided to go and wake her up together,
kalian akhirnya memutuskan untuk pergi membangunkannya bersama.
but you found Hagie dead.
Tapi ketika kalian tiba di sana, dia sudah dibunuh.
Yes.
Ya.
Who was the first one to go wake Hagie up?
Siapa yang pertama membangunkan Hagie?
It was me.
Aku.
I called out to her several times but got no answer.
Aku memanggil dia beberapa kali, tapi tidak ada jawaban.
She was sleeping even after I finished sewing on the button,
Dia masih tidur ketika aku selesai memasang kancing,
so I went back to the break room where Someka and Rumi were waiting.
jadi aku kembali ke ruang istirahat di mana Someka dan Rumi sedang menunggu.
-Button? -I was going to sew the button
-Kancing? -Ketika aku setuju untuk menjahit
that was almost ready to come off from Someka's jacket,
kancing jaket Someka yang lepas,
but found out that I had left the sewing kit at the studio.
aku sadar aku melupakan peralatan jahitku di dalam studio.
This must be it.
Pasti ini.
When Tadako entered the room.
Ketika Tadako memasuki ruangan.
Half of your body is hidden,
Setengah tubuhnya tersembunyi,
but it's obvious that you're sewing.
tapi kau bisa tahu dia sedang menjahit sesuatu pada jaket itu.
But, it looks as if you've been here for more than 10 minutes.
Kau di sana selama lebih dari 10 menit.
Does it take that much time just to sew on a button?
Apa sungguh selama itu untuk menjahit sebuah kancing?
Yeah, when I took a look,
Ketika aku melihat lebih teliti,
I saw that cuff of her sleeve was coming a bit apart.
aku menyadari pinggir lengannya juga lepas.
True! The cuff's been fixed.
Kau benar, sudah diperbaiki.
So, who's the next one that went to wake her up?
Siapa yang pergi untuk membangunkannya kemudian?
Me.
Aku.
My guitar's getting a tune up so I rented one from this shop.
Gitarku sedang diperbaiki, jadi aku meminjam dari studio.
While I was practicing, the string of the guitar broke.
Tapi satu senarnya putus selama latihan.
I thought I'd try waking her while I replaced the string.
Aku pikir aku akan coba membangunkan dia selagi mengganti senarnya.
The reason why all four of us took a break from practice
Senar yang putus itu adalah alasan kami berempat berhenti latihan,
was because my guitar string broke too.
dan pergi untuk beristirahat.
If you rented the guitar from here,
Jika kau menyewa gitar itu dari studio,
couldn't you have had the shop clerk change the string for you?
tak bisakah kau meminta staf mereka untuk mengganti senarnya?
I wanted to replace the string and tune the guitar myself!
Aku ingin mengganti senar dan menyetelnya sendiri!
Oh, this is you, isn't it, Someka?
Ini Someka, bukan?
It's when you're replacing the string and tuning your guitar.
Ini kau sedang mengganti senar dan menyetel gitarnya.
Yes, that's right.
Ya, itu benar.
But, you've got to turn up the volume to tune the guitar, don't you?
Tapi bukankah menyetel membuat suara?
You're pretty close to the drums, aren't you?
Dan kau berdiri cukup dekat ke drum itu.
I figured I'd deliberately make noise and wake her up!
Aku dengan sengaja membuat suara agar dia bangun.
I wanted to hurry and get on with practice, so...
Aku ingin mulai latihan lagi.
How did Hagie look back then?
Bagaimana tampaknya Hagie saat itu?
She had her face on the high tom of the drums and was sleeping.
Menunduk di depan drum dan wajahnya tertutup oleh lengan.
She always slept like that.
Hagie selalu tidur seperti itu.
So if she was already dead by that point...
Jadi jika dia sudah tewas pada saat itu...
You wouldn't have known.
Kau tidak akan tahu.
Don't tell me that
Apa kau ingin mengatakan
you're insinuating that I did it when I went there at the beginning?
aku membunuhnya ketika aku masuk lebih dulu?
I was just stating an example.
Kita hanya bicara secara hipotesis.
So, the last one to go wake her up was you, Rumi?
Rumi, apa kau yang terakhir membangunkan dia?
Yes.
Ya.
The fact is, I found a part in a song that I wanted to change.
Selama latihan, sebenarnya ada bagian lagu yang ingin aku ubah.
So I went to make the change while at the same time to wake her up.
Aku pikir aku bisa membangunkannya selagi mengerjakan lagu itu.
If you take a look at the music sheet I left back at the studio,
Jika kau melihat lembaran musik yang ada di studio,
I think you'll understand what I mean.
aku pikir kau akan mengerti apa yang kumaksudkan.
Let's see.
Mari kita lihat.
It's true that there are parts that look to have been re-written.
Benar ada yang telah diubah.
You changed this part to up tempo, right?
Kau membuat bagian ini bertempo cepat, bukan?
Yep.
Ya.
I think this is better because it has more beat to it!
Ini jauh lebih baik!
It's all Greek to me.
Aku tidak mengerti.
Well, but now that Hagie is dead,
Dengan tewasnya Hagie,
I don't know if we'll have the chance to play that song anymore though.
kita mungkin takkan bisa menyanyikan lagu itu lagi.
There, there!
Dia ada dalam video!
But, Rumi, you're moving your keyboard.
Tapi, Rumi, kau memindahkan keyboardnya.
I moved away from the drums so I wouldn't wake Hagie.
Aku menjauh dari drum agar aku tidak membangunkan Hagie.
I wanted Hagie to listen to the song after I finished revising it and all,
Aku ingin Hagie mendengar lagu itu setelah aku selesai memperbaikinya,
so I kept the volume down really low too.
jadi aku memainkannya sepelan mungkin.
I finished revising and called out to her but got no answer.
Aku memanggilnya ketika aku sudah selesai, tapi dia tidak menjawab.
You seem to have been at the studio for about 10 minutes too?
Sepertinya kau juga berada di dalam studio sekitar 10 menit.
Okay, we're going to search for the rope like murder weapon
Yah, kami akan mencari senar yang digunakan
that Hagie was killed with.
untuk mencekik Hagie.
After all three of you go through a body check,
Setelah menjalani pemeriksaan badan, aku ingin kalian bertiga
please wait at the break room in the basement.
menunggu di ruang istirahat di ruang bawah.
What? You can't find the murder weapon?
Apa? Kau tak bisa menemukan senjata pembunuhnya?
Did you search every nook and cranny?
Apa kau sudah mencari seluruh area ini?
Yes, we searched all over the studio
Ya, dari setiap ruang latihan
including the bathroom and inside the drain as well.
termasuk kamar mandi dan di dalam saluran pembuangan juga.
Her ETD is around just when the three girls
Perkiraan waktu kematian adalah ketika mereka bertiga
went to the studio to wake her up.
pergi ke studio untuk membangunkan korban.
According to the security camera of this shop
Menurut kamera keamanan toko
that's set up by the entrance,
di pintu masuk,
those three did not go outside.
mereka bertiga belum pergi ke luar.
If no weapon was found on the bodies of the girls,
Dan jika pemeriksaan tubuh tidak menemukan senjata itu,
the murder weapon has to be somewhere in this room.
maka itu pasti berada di sekitar sini.
Search harder!
Cari lebih cermat!
Yes, sir.
Ya, pak.
Did something happen?
Apa sesuatu terjadi?
There were police cars parked outside,
Ada sebuah mobil polisi yang diparkir di luar.
but is it a case or something?
Apakah sebuah kasus?
No, it's nothing really...
Yah, um...
What's the matter, Sera?
Ada apa, Sera?
Do you suspect them?
Menurutmu mereka melakukannya?
Oh, no.
Oh, tidak.
It's just that seeing somebody carrying a guitar case
Ketika aku melihat orang membawa tempat gitar di punggung mereka,
brings back memories.
itu membawa kembali kenangan.
It reminds me of 4 years ago
Aku teringat 4 tahun yang lalu,
when I watched Shu standing on the other side of the platform
ketika aku melihat Shu berdiri di sisi seberang peron kereta
carrying a guitar case!
dengan sebuah gitar di punggungnya.
Shu?
Shu?
So, is she Mr. Akai's younger sister after all?
Apa itu artinya dia sebenarnya adalah adik perempuan Akai?
I was surprised.
Aku terkejut.
Because I thought he was in the States.
Aku pikir dia ada di Amerika.
And I never saw Shu do music too.
Dan aku tak pernah melihat dia memainkan instrumen apapun sebelumnya.
Back then, I was on my way back after watching a movie with a friend,
Aku sedang dalam perjalanan pulang dari bioskop dengan teman-temanku,
but ran and got on the same train as Shu!
tapi aku berlari ke peron seberang dan naik kereta yang sama dengan Shu!
I really wanted to listen to Shu playing the guitar.
Aku sangat ingin mendengarnya memainkan gitar itu.
Really?
Benarkah?
What happened next?
Apa yang terjadi berikutnya?
Shu found me on one of the station platforms
Dia menemukanku di peron stasiun
where I transferred trains several times.
setelah berganti kereta beberapa kali.
He scolded me telling me to go home
Dia marah padaku dan menyuruhku untuk pulang,
but when I told him
tapi ketika aku memberitahunya
I didn't have any money and didn't know how to get home,
aku tidak punya uang dan tidak tahu cara pulang,
he left me on the platform after telling me to wait
dia menyuruhku untuk menunggu di sana
while he goes and buys me a ticket.
selagi dia membelikan aku tiket dan meninggalkanku di peron.
To tell the truth, I was already in intermediate school
Sejak aku masih SMP,
so I had money and knew how to get home too,
aku sebenarnya punya uang, dan aku tahu cara pulang.
but to him, I guess I was still a child.
Tapi kupikir Shu pasti masih melihatku seperti anak kecil.
And? Did you wait like he told to?
Apa kau menunggu seperti yang dia katakan?
Yeah. I felt like crying.
Ya. Aku ingin menangis.
But back then the man that Shu was with...
Tapi pria yang bersama Shu mengatakan...
You.
Hei, kau.
Do you like music?
Apa kau suka musik?
After saying that, he took the bass out of the case
Lalu dia mengeluarkan bas miliknya dari tempatnya
and taught me how to play a scale.
dan mengajariku cara untuk memainkan tangga nada.
Oh.
Benarkah?
So the person you mentioned earlier that taught you the bass...
Jadi orang yang mengajarimu cara bermain bas yang kau sebutkan tadi...
It was him?
Itu dia?
Yeah. It was only for about 10 minutes though.
Ya, walau itu hanya sekitar 10 menit.
Then maybe he was your big brother's music friend?
Mungkin dia adalah teman band kakakmu.
I wonder about that.
Aku tidak tahu tentang itu.
The bass that the person had was in a soft case.
Dia membawa basnya di dalam sebuah tempat yang lembut.
But it didn't change form and stayed upright
Tapi bahkan setelah dia mengeluarkannya,
even after he took the bass out.
bentuknya tetap sama dan berdiri tegak.
Maybe the bass was just camouflage
Mungkin bas itu adalah kamuflase
and something harder was inside the case.
untuk sesuatu yang keras yang dia simpan di dalam tas itu.
A rifle.
Sebuah senapan.
And? And?
Dan? Dan?
Did you get his name?
Apa dia memberitahumu namanya?
No, I didn't.
Tidak.
But another man who came to the platform called him.
Tapi pria lain yang datang ke peron memanggil dia.
Scotch!
Scotch!
Scotch?
Scotch?
He was non-Japanese?
Apa dia orang asing?
He looked Japanese no matter how I looked at him
Dia jelas orang Jepang,
so I think it was just a nickname.
jadi mungkin itu nama panggilannya.
But, the man who called him that
Tapi pria yang memanggil dia
had his hat deep over his eyes
yang mengenakan topi lebih rendah dari matanya,
so I didn't get a good view of what he looked like.
jadi aku tidak melihat wajahnya dengan jelas.
He looked very similar to you, Amuro!
Tapi aku ada firasat dia mirip sepertimu, Amuro!
It's someone else.
Kau salah orang.
Never mind such old time stories.
Bagaimanapun, daripada membicarakan tentang masa lalu,
Why don't we get to solving the case that just happened here?
kenapa kita tidak memecahkan kasus yang sedang terjadi sekarang?
You're a detective too, aren't you?
Kau juga seorang detektif, bukan?
Yeah, I guess so.
Ya, kau benar.
It's just as the girls say.
Seperti kata mereka,
I guess we need to investigate the members of other bands too.
sepertinya kita harus memeriksa anggota band lainnya.
Come to think of it, I'd like to watch the video recording
Dipikir-pikir, aku ingin melihat video latihan
of your practice session at the studio!
yang katamu kau rekam di studio.
Sure!
Tentu.
We switched the power off when we weren't practicing
Aku mematikannya karena kami tidak sedang latihan,
so I don't think the perp would be displayed.
jadi kami tidak punya video pelakunya.
See!
Lihat?
I see.
Begitu.
So, that's the story.
Jadi seperti itu.
Next Conan,
Selanjutnya dalam Conan,
"A Girls' Band on Bad Terms (Part 2)"
"Band Wanita Yang Tidak Ramah (Bagian 2)"
Next Conan's Hint:
Petunjuk Conan Selanjutnya:
"Knitted cap"
"Topi rajut"
You're still too young for Scotch.
Kau terlalu kecil untuk Scotch.
How about Bourbon then?
Bagaimana dengan Bourbon?
-That's fine. -That won't do either, will it?
-Tidak apa-apa. -Kau pasti bercanda.